Thank you.
谢谢。
The
这
¶¶
¶¶
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right, welcome back, everybody, to another session of the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship
好的，欢迎回来，每个人，参加以太坊协议奖学金的另一届会议
study group.
研究小组。
This is week seven on the research track, and today we have three guests with us, Ignacio,
这是研究轨道上的第七周，今天我们有三位客人，Ignacio，
Guillaume and Josh from the StateOS team at the Ethereum Foundation here to talk about
以太坊基金会州立大学队的吉拉姆和乔什在这里谈论
The Verge, which consists mostly of the upgrade to Verkle trees.
该边缘主要由升级到Verkle树组成。
So, yeah, I don't know, Mario, how you want to do this introduction here for all three
所以，是的，我不知道，马里奥，您想在这里如何进行此介绍
of them, but good luck.
他们，但是祝你好运。
Yeah, thank you so much.
是的，非常感谢。
Thank you so much, guys, for joining us today.
非常感谢，伙计们，今天加入了我们。
Yeah, it's pretty heavy on introductions.
是的，介绍非常沉重。
I probably won't spend too much time on it.
我可能不会花太多时间在上面。
I just want to welcome you all to the research track of this week.
我只想欢迎大家参加本周的研究轨道。
The Virgo trees are very interesting topic, very important topic happening right now.
处女座树是非常有趣的话题，目前正在发生非常重要的话题。
And it's it's kind of hard to grasp if you don't have the cryptography inside and the Virgo trees background.
如果您没有内部的密码学和处女座树的背景，这很难掌握。
So we have three speakers today to cover their their parts of this research.
因此，今天我们有三位发言人来介绍他们的这项研究部分。
it's Josh from the EF research team, but Josh hasn't been just Ethereum researcher, he's been
是EF研究团队的乔什（Josh），但乔什（Josh）不仅仅是以太坊研究人员
doing a bunch of cool stuff even before, I believe he worked in Intel and Slack and many interesting
甚至在以前做很多很酷的事情，我相信他在Intel和Slack工作，还有很多有趣的事情
projects. Guillaume is actually from Get team, from the go Ethereum team, so he contributes to
项目。 Guillaume实际上来自Go Team，来自GO以太坊团队，因此他为
Get but mostly works on this vertical tree migration transition, and Ignacio is from
获得，但主要是在此垂直树迁移过渡上起作用，而Ignacio来自
that research as well uh however the interesting uh piece about ignacio is that he actually has
但是，这项研究也是关于Ignacio的有趣的uh，是他实际上
been followed in the epf course three so he's uh he's a prime example here of a uh successful um
在EPF课程三中遵循，所以他是UH成功的一个很好的例子
epf fellow as somebody who's been uh diving into ethereum and studying this similarly to
EPF研究员是一直潜入以太坊的人
many people in the audience now and uh today he's on the cutting edge of these technologies so it's
现在听众中的许多人，今天他处于这些技术的最前沿，所以
it's an honor to have you here folks, all of you,
很荣幸让你在这里，你们所有人，
and I'm very excited to see your presentation.
我很高兴看到您的演讲。
I hope we'll manage to coordinate it.
我希望我们能协调它。
So who's starting?
那么谁开始？
Who will pick it up?
谁会捡起它？
I will start.
我会开始的。
Okay, go ahead.
好吧，继续。
The stage is yours.
舞台是你的。
Okay, thank you.
好吧，谢谢。
Okay, well, first of all, thank all for being here.
好吧，首先，感谢所有人在这里。
We are pretty excited that more people
我们很兴奋，更多的人
are interested in local trees.
对当地树有兴趣。
So this presentation aims to be some,
因此，本演讲旨在成为一些
let's say, technical introduction to the topic.
假设该主题的技术介绍。
We won't expect everybody to understand 100%
我们不会指望每个人都能100％
of what we'll show,
我们将显示的内容
because many of these things are pretty hairy,
因为其中许多事情都很毛茸茸，所以
and probably if you're interested in this topic,
如果您对此主题感兴趣，可能
you will come back to this slide after the talk.
演讲后，您将回到这张幻灯片。
So, just to talk a bit more about our team, our team is composed of Guillaume, which is
因此，只是为了更多地谈论我们的团队，我们的团队由Guillaume组成，这是
the team lead, and also part of the guest team.
团队领导，也是客串团队的一部分。
Then it's Ignacio, which is me.
然后是Ignacio，就是我。
Then we have Sjoch, that also help us with all the community organisation, calls, moderations,
然后，我们有Sjoch，这也可以帮助我们完成所有社区组织，呼叫，适中，
and interacting with other teams
并与其他团队互动
because the vertical tree change really has a lot of impact.
因为垂直树的变化确实具有很大的影响。
And also we have Kev that is related to a lot of work
而且我们还有与大量工作有关的KEV
in the cryptography side.
在加密方面。
We also maintain a website, which is vertical.info
我们还维护一个网站，该网站是垂直的。
where it's kind of a landing page
在哪里着陆页
for the vertical tree change,
对于垂直树的变化，
where you can find what vertical trees is about,
在哪里可以找到垂直树的内容，
what is the motivation, which is the current tasks
什么是动机，这是当前的任务
that we and others are working.
我们和其他人正在工作。
And also we have some links to some articles and videos
而且我们还有一些指向一些文章和视频的链接
where we talk about Virgo.
我们谈论处女座的地方。
So let's start a bit with the motivation of the change,
因此，让我们从变化的动力开始，
which is probably the correct way of trying to understand
这可能是尝试理解的正确方法
any kind of change in the protocol,
协议中的任何更改，
because at least with big changes,
因为至少有很大的变化，
they are usually rooted in kind of defending important values of the 3D protocol.
它们通常植根于捍卫3D协议的重要值。
So if we kind of take a step back and think about systems or applications in general,
因此，如果我们退后一步，考虑系统或应用程序，
stateful applications are usually pretty complex.
状态应用通常非常复杂。
Usually the state part of the system is what creates many of the big challenges, such as
通常，系统的一部分是造成许多大挑战的原因，例如
That's how do you access the state in an efficient way?
这就是如何有效地访问状态？
How do you save the state?
您如何保存州？
Because usually the state of the system is where most of the value is.
因为通常系统的状态是大多数值。
So stateful applications are usually pretty complex.
因此，状态应用程序通常非常复杂。
Usually state only grows with time, which is usually a pain and something that creates
通常状态只会随时间而生长，这通常是痛苦，而创造的东西
many problems.
许多问题。
And if we think about what state means for Ethereum blockchain, the important effect
而且，如果我们考虑状态对以太坊区块链的意义，那么重要的效果
is that they put a lot of pressure on some core values that we want to defend.
是他们对我们想要捍卫的一些核心价值施加了很大的压力。
Being more concrete, if you want to be a node and validate blocks, unfortunately you will
更具体，如果您想成为一个节点并验证块，不幸的是，您将
need first to download all the state of the network, which is somewhat big, so it takes
首先需要下载所有网络状态，这有点大，因此需要
some time. That means that you also have to save it somewhere, of course, and from some
一段时间。这意味着您当然也必须将其保存在某个地方，并从某些地方保存
numbers that Guillaume told me in his setup, you will need about 1.5 terabytes of disk
Guillaume在他的设置中告诉我的数字，您将需要大约1.5吨的磁盘
space. So probably a good recommendation is having a two-terabyte disk. The requirement
空间。因此，可能有一个很好的建议是具有两型磁盘。要求
will only increase with time, which is very unfortunate.
只会随着时间而增加，这是非常不幸的。
And also the way that Ethereum handles state
以及以太坊处理状态的方式
isn't CK friendly, which also gets a bit in the way
不是CK友好，这也有点有些
of even more future changes
更加未来的变化
that we want to make through the protocol.
我们想通过协议做出。
So let's think about how we can have a better stateless world.
因此，让我们考虑一下如何拥有一个更好的无状态世界。
The ideal goal here is that whenever a node wants to join the network it doesn't have
这里的理想目标是，每当节点想要加入网络时，
to sync all the states.
同步所有州。
And indirectly that means that you don't need a huge disk for storing all the states.
这间接意味着您不需要大型磁盘来存储所有州。
So the main idea is that you download the execution client and the consensus client,
因此，主要想法是您下载执行客户端和共识客户端，
configure everything, you join the network, and you can start validating blocks as fast as possible
配置所有内容，您加入网络，您可以尽快开始验证块
without requiring a big disk. Also, part of doing this change is trying to make the protocol more
不需要大磁盘。另外，进行此更改的一部分是试图使协议更多
CK-friendly so in the future we can use snarks to create proof of computation as to validate that
ck友好型，将来我们可以使用snark来创建计算证明，以验证该计算
that the block execution has been done correctly.
块执行已正确完成。
So, like the main idea is that Virkle-tree
因此，就像主要的想法是Virkle-Tree
kind of solve the storage problem of nodes.
解决节点的存储问题。
So at least a stateless client can avoid having
因此，至少无状态客户可以避免
even a separate storage for Ethereum state.
即使是以太坊状态的单独存储。
And in the future with snarks,
在将来与Snarks一起
nodes can even verify a computational proof that the block is valid instead of doing the actual
节点甚至可以验证块有效而不是进行实际的计算证明
execution themselves. So this is going in the direction of trying to reduce hardware requirements
自己执行。因此，这朝着尝试减少硬件要求的方向发展
for nodes. It also simplifies anyone that wants to try building a stateless client, because if you
用于节点。它还简化了想要尝试建立无状态客户端的任何人，因为如果您
If you don't know how to deal with storing a big state,
如果您不知道如何处理大量状态，
you don't have all this complexity of efficient ways
您没有所有这些有效方法的复杂性
of storing things in this,
在其中存储东西，
how to access this data efficiently and all that.
如何有效地访问这些数据以及所有这些数据。
You can simply access data that just fits in memory.
您可以简单地访问仅适用于内存的数据。
This change also allows potentially
这种变化也允许
to increase the gas limit, which is like a hot topic now.
增加气体限制，这就像一个热门话题。
This isn't something that we'll do in the vertical fork,
这不是我们在垂直叉中做的事情，
but it's something that maybe it will be allowed
但这也许会被允许
in the future.
将来。
And finally,
最后，
this change is also maybe pushing
这种变化也可能在推动
in the direction in which different nodes
在不同节点的方向上
might have different more specialized roles
可能具有不同的专业角色
in the protocol,
在协议中，
which can have some interesting impact
可能会产生一些有趣的影响
in the staking for nodes.
在淋巴结中的积分中。
But yeah, that's more like a research area.
但是，是的，这更像是一个研究领域。
So, if you want to explain how Broccoli Trees work or what it's like a single way, like
因此，如果您想解释西兰花树的工作方式或一种单一的方式，
a simple way to explain this change is that Broccoli Trees basically introduce something
解释这种变化的一种简单方法是西兰花树基本上引入了某些东西
new in the protocol which is called an execution witness.
该协议中的新事物被称为执行证人。
And this execution witness basically contains all the data that you need to verify a block.
该执行证人基本上包含您需要验证块的所有数据。
So the reason that today you need to download all the states before verifying blocks is
因此，今天您需要在验证块之前下载所有州的原因是
that whenever you receive a block, let's say that you have a single block, and this block
每当您收到一个块时，假设您有一个块，那么这个块
has a single transaction in which I send 10 ETH to Mario.
我有一项交易，我将10 ETH发送给Mario。
So if you want to verify this block, that means that you will need to know my current
因此，如果您想验证此块，这意味着您需要知道我的当前
balance because if you don't have that, you're going to verify that sending 10 ETH is a valid
平衡是因为如果您没有那个，您将验证发送10个ETH是有效的
transaction, right?
交易，对吗？
And since you cannot really predict which will be the transactions in the next block,
而且，由于您无法真正预测哪个将是下一个块中的交易，所以
that basically means that you need all the states to be sure that you can verify the next block.
这基本上意味着您需要所有状态才能确保可以验证下一个块。
So, the idea is that whenever, like, buckle tweet happens, you can receive some extra data,
因此，想法是，每当发生扣子推文时，您都可以收到一些额外的数据，
apart from the block, which is called the witness, which contains all the states that is accessed
除了被称为证人的街区，其中包含所有已访问的州
in this block such that everything that you will need to validate the block will be found
在此块中，您需要验证该块的所有内容
in this witness.
在这个证人中。
This isn't really a new idea.
这并不是一个新想法。
This is something that has been explored before.
这是以前已经探索过的东西。
Even you can do this with the current tree.
即使您也可以使用当前树来做到这一点。
But the problem is that you cannot really trust whoever gives you this data because
但是问题在于，您不能真正相信任何给您这些数据的人，因为
this data can be anything, right?
这些数据可以是什么，对吗？
I can simply invent that my balance is whatever.
我可以简单地发明我的平衡就是什么。
And if you simply trust this witness data to validate the block,
如果您简单地相信此证人数据以验证该块，则
you might reach a false conclusion that the transaction is correct
您可能会得出一个错误的结论，即交易是正确的
when it isn't.
当不是。
So what is needed is cryptographic proof
因此，需要的是加密证明
that this witness data is correct,
这个证人数据是正确的，
which is basically similar to a Merkle proof.
基本上类似于默克尔的证明。
But what Verkle allows is making this cryptographic proof be really small, such that the complete
但是Verkle允许的是使此加密证明确实很小，因此完整
witness size it is small enough to make this viable.
见证大小足够小，可以使这个可行。
And another really interesting thing is that this witness also contains all the code that
另一个真正有趣的事情是，该证人还包含所有代码
will need to execute contracts, which is something pretty weird for people because they don't
将需要执行合同，这对人们来说很奇怪，因为他们没有
actually know that the contract code doesn't really live in the tree.
实际上知道合同代码并不真正存在于树上。
So yeah, to validate a block, you only need balances and storage slots.
是的，要验证一个块，您只需要余额和存储插槽即可。
You actually need the contract code.
您实际上需要合同代码。
So making Ethereum stateless sounds interesting, but unfortunately it isn't really a simple
因此，使以太坊的无状态听起来很有趣，但不幸的是，这并不是一个简单的
task.
任务。
We need to introduce a new cryptography stack, we need to introduce a new data structure,
我们需要引入一个新的密码堆栈，我们需要引入一个新的数据结构，
we have to do some gas accounting changes, and we have to migrate all the data from the
我们必须进行一些气体会计更改，我们必须从
Merkle-Bartusza tree to the Berko tree.
Merkle-Bartusza树到Berko树。
So now we will explore all these points in more detail.
因此，现在我们将更详细地探索所有这些要点。
So let's start with the cryptography, which is the thing that is at the lowest layer.
因此，让我们从密码学开始，这是最低层的东西。
As usually happens in blockchains, whenever you think about some new super cool feature
每当您考虑一些新的超级酷功能时，通常会发生在区块链中
that seems almost impossible, you will find that there's like a cryptography scheme that
这似乎几乎是不可能的，您会发现有一个加密计划
is really what allows this magic to happen.
确实是使这种魔术发生的原因。
In this case for BrokerTrees, the magic happens in this cryptographic proof that the witness is
在这种情况下，对于经纪人来说，魔术发生在这个加密证明中，证人是
correct, while having this proof size be really small. So this is allowed by the cryptography
正确，让此证明尺寸真的很小。这是密码学允许的
that is used in BrokerTrees, it's really what allows this witness to be transmitted
这是在经纪人中使用的，这实际上是允许该证人传播的原因
it within with each block, which is something that should reach every stateless client.
它在每个块中，这是可以到达每个无状态客户端的东西。
And ultimately, this is what allows Ethereum to be to continue being a trustless
最终，这就是使以太坊继续成为无信任的原因
protocol, so each stateless client can verify the block without trusting any other party.
协议，因此每个无状态客户端都可以在不信任任何其他方的情况下验证块。
This is done because this cryptographic proof really gives this stateless client the
这是因为此加密证明确实使这个无状态客户端
guarantee that this data is correct without trusting other parties that have the full state.
确保此数据是正确的，而不会信任具有完整状态的其他各方。
The basic ingredients of the cryptography are vector commitments, inner product argument,
加密的基本成分是向量承诺，内部产品参数，
and multi-proofs. So, we will talk about them next. But before doing that,
和多个防护措施。因此，接下来我们将谈论他们。但是在此之前，
let's try to do a refresher on what cryptography we use today in the stage 3.
让我们尝试对我们今天在第3阶段使用的密码学进行复习。
So, today, we use something called the Merkle Patricia tree, which probably you have heard
因此，今天，我们使用了所谓的默克尔·帕特里夏树（Merkle Patricia Tree）的东西，您可能已经听到了
before.
前。
The kind of cryptography used here is pretty simple.
这里使用的那种密码学很简单。
We simply use Sketchhack cryptographic hash function.
我们只需使用Sketchhack加密哈希功能。
The way it works it's similar to a Merkle tree, but we have a different kind of structure
它的工作方式类似于默克尔树，但是我们有另一种结构
with a different branching factor.
具有不同的分支因子。
So instead of a branching factor of two,
因此，而不是两个分支因素，而是
Merkle Patricia trees have a branching factor of 16,
Merkle Patricia树的分支系数为16个，
have this extension nodes,
有此扩展节点，
and the way you kind of point from one parent to the child,
以及您从一个父母到孩子的观点的方式，
you use, you hash the node.
您使用，哈希节点。
So hashes are a way of doing something called
因此，哈希是一种做事的方式
content addressing,
内容介绍，
which is a really deep and important concept in blockchains.
这是区块链中非常深刻而重要的概念。
So, hashes are like pointers that define kind of the identity of each node.
因此，散列就像指示了每个节点的身份的指示。
But like the TLDR is that we use Ketchak for the cryptography of the Merkle Patricia tree.
但是，就像TLDR一样，我们将凯奇克（Ketchak）用于默克尔·帕特里夏树（Merkle Patricia Tree）的密码学。
In Merkle trees, we stop using Ketchak. We use something that is called vector commitment.
在默克尔树上，我们停止使用凯奇克。我们使用称为向量承诺的东西。
So, the idea here is that we have vectors of 256 elements.
因此，这里的想法是我们有256个元素的向量。
And each item of this vector is a scalar field element.
该向量的每个项目都是标量字段元素。
So, this is like maybe a technical term, but you can think about this as, like, numbers.
因此，这可能是一个技术术语，但是您可以将其视为数字。
Okay?
好的？
And we have a commit function which allows you to provide this vector and receive what
而且我们有一个提交功能，可让您提供此向量并接收什么
we call a commitment.
我们称承诺。
Okay?
好的？
This commitment is like something similar to a hash in the sense that it's binding.
从某种意义上说，这种承诺就像与哈希相似的东西。
So what binding means is that if you change anything about the vector, this commitment
因此，有约束力的意思是，如果您更改有关向量的任何内容，则该承诺
will change.
会改变。
So you cannot really fake.
所以你不能真正伪造。
After you have a commitment, you can find another vector that maps to the same commitment.
承诺后，您可以找到另一个映射到相同承诺的向量。
So, that is kind of a really important property.
因此，这是一个非常重要的财产。
Something else that you can do is you can use this prove and verify functions.
您可以做的其他事情是您可以使用此证明并验证功能。
So, these functions, the prove function basically receives a vector and an index, and it will
因此，这些功能，证明函数基本上接收一个向量和索引，它将
generates a pie which represents a proof that the element at that index is whatever value is in that
生成一个代表该索引上的元素是该元素的派
index. So basically you can prove that the element at position two is 10 or whatever.
指数。因此，基本上，您可以证明位置二的元素是10或其他。
And you also have this verify function which receives the commitment of the vector,
而且您还拥有此验证功能，该功能接收了向量的承诺，
the index, the claimed value that is in that index,
该索引，该指数中的声称价值，
the proof, and it returns false or true
证明，它返回错误或真实
depending if this proof is correct
取决于此证明是否正确
that the item in this index is that value.
该索引中的项目是该值。
Note that in this verify function,
请注意，在此验证函数中，
what the verifier needs is only the commitment.
验证者需要的只是承诺。
It doesn't need the vector,
它不需要向量，
which is where the magic happens, okay?
哪个魔术发生了，好吗？
So the magic here is that you can verify an item in the vector only having the commitment
因此，这里的魔术是您只能在向量中验证一个项目，只有承诺
and this proof that it's much smaller than having the full vector, right?
这证明它比拥有完整矢量要小得多，对吗？
That's kind of the main point.
这是重点。
Going more into the gory details, this vector commitment and proving scheme is used under
更多地介绍了血腥的细节，此向量承诺和证明方案在下面使用
a setup of a new elliptic curve that we introduced in the protocol which is called bandersnatch.
我们在协议中引入的新椭圆曲线的设置称为BanderSnatch。
We also used another abstraction on top which is called banderwagon to remove the cofactor and
我们还在顶部使用了另一个称为banderwagon的抽象来删除辅因子和
make the group safe. The scalar field of this curve is 256, 53 bits and the base field is 255
使小组安全。该曲线的标量场是256、53位，基地为255
bits. This elliptic curve doesn't have pairings, which is good because it means smaller fields,
位。这款椭圆曲线没有配对，这很好，因为它意味着较小的字段，
so the operations can be more efficient. This bandersnatch curve it was created
因此，操作可以更有效。这是创建的bandersnatch曲线
with an intention of being what is called an embedded curve in the VLS12-3-H1.
目的是成为VLS12-3-H1中所谓的嵌入曲线。
So, basically, the base field of bandersnatch is the scalar field of VLS12-3-H1.
因此，基本上，BandersNatch的基础场是VLS12-3-H1的标量场。
The reason for this is that if you want to do snarks using VLS12-3-H1, that means that the elliptic core operations in Bandersnatch are basically native field operations.
这样做的原因是，如果您想使用VLS12-3-H1进行鼻涕，则意味着Bandersnatch中的椭圆形核心操作基本上是本地现场操作。
So in a circuit, you have to emulate fields, which is really inefficient.
因此，在电路中，您必须效仿效率低下的字段。
This inner product argument is what it's like the proven scheme that we use for this vector
这个内部产品参数是我们用于此向量的验证方案的样子
openings that I showed in the previous slides.
我在上一个幻灯片中显示的开口。
An important property is that it doesn't require trusted setup.
一个重要的属性是它不需要值得信赖的设置。
So if you kind of compare it with KCG commitments using blobs, that requires a trusted setup,
因此，如果您将其与使用Blobs的KCG承诺进行比较，则需要一个值得信赖的设置，
which adds extra overhead whenever you are doing the configuration of the prooving scheme.
每当您进行竞争方案的配置时，都会增加额外的开销。
We don't have to do that for Brocol trees, which is nice.
我们不必为Brocol Trees做到这一点，这很好。
We use an extra prooving scheme, which is called multi-proof, which allows to aggregate
我们使用额外的挑战方案，该方案称为多型，允许汇总
multiple openings in a single one.
一个单个开口。
That is really important because it makes it even shorter.
这确实很重要，因为它使其更短。
So, let's go now to the data structure and try to understand more how the Virkle tree
因此，让我们现在进入数据结构，并尝试了解更多的virkle树
data structure works.
数据结构有效。
So, the change in the data structure of the theorem protocol it's basically switching
因此，定理协议的数据结构的更改基本上是切换
from the Markle Patricia tree to the Virkle tree.
从Markle Patricia树到Virkle树。
The Virkle tree name comes from a mix of vector commitment and Markle tree.
Virkle树名称来自向量承诺和Markle树的混合。
So, hopefully now that makes a bit more sense.
因此，希望现在这会更有意义。
So, if you remember how, like, these trees are using the protocol, I think that there
因此，如果您记得这些树木正在使用协议，我认为
is a really nice image here in which you can see that if you see the state root of the
是一个非常好的图像，您可以看到，如果您看到
block header, that is the state root of the world state tree.
块标头，这是世界状态树的状态根。
Basically, this tree is a tree of trees.
基本上，这棵树是一棵树。
So in the leaf nodes, we have EOA accounts and smart contract accounts.
因此，在叶节点中，我们有EOA帐户和智能合约帐户。
So for EOA accounts, you have basically the nodes and the balance.
因此，对于EOA帐户，您基本上具有节点和余额。
But for smart contracts, you also have the storage root, which is basically the root of another tree that holds all the storage slots of that contract.
但是对于智能合约，您还拥有存储根，这基本上是另一棵树的根，该根始于合同的所有存储插槽。
So that's why we say that this is like a tree of trees.
这就是为什么我们说这就像一棵树。
So this is kind of how things look like for the state storage in the protocol today.
因此，对于当今协议中的状态存储来说，这是一种看起来的样子。
This will change. So the first thing to say is that we will stop having this tree of trees.
这将改变。因此，首先要说的是我们将不再拥有这棵树。
We will have a single tree. So we will have all the balances of accounts and all the storage
我们将有一棵树。因此，我们将拥有所有帐户和所有存储的余额
slots of all contracts all in the same tree. So that's kind of the first big difference.
所有合同的插槽全部在同一棵树中。因此，这是第一个大区别。
The other big difference is that the tree shape is pretty different too.
另一个很大的区别是，树的形状也大不相同。
We have here an image that I took from a really nice article that I invite everyone
我们在这里有一张我从一篇非常好的文章中拍摄的图像，我邀请所有人
to read it in more detail, I left here the link. So, to explain this a bit, we basically have
要更详细地阅读它，我在这里留下了链接。因此，要解释一下，我们基本上有
two kind of nodes. We have internal nodes which have a branching factor of 256,
两种节点。我们的内部节点的分支系数为256，
which is another change, another difference compared to the Merkle-Patrifici which has
这是另一个变化
branching factor of 16. So this increase in branching factor allows the tree to be
分支系数为16。因此，分支系数的增加允许树为
shallower which is really nice because that means that if you kind of think of
较浅，这真的很好，因为那意味着如果您想到
analogy from analogy from a Merkle position tree, a Merkle position tree
类比默克尔位置树的类比，默克尔位置树
usually has a branching factor of two so that means that you need log in base two
通常具有两个分支系数，因此您需要登录两个
elements to really create a proof and if you have a branching factor of 256 then
真正创建证据的元素，如果您的分支系数为256，则
then you have log in base 256 elements.
然后，您将登录基本256个元素。
So that is much better for size.
因此，这对尺寸要好得多。
And apart from internal nodes,
除了内部节点，
we have what we call extension level commitments
我们有我们所说的扩展级承诺
and suffix level commitments.
和后缀级别的承诺。
Basically the idea here is that the three keys are 32 bytes.
基本上，这里的想法是三个键是32个字节。
32 bytes, so that is the same as today. And the first 31 bytes defines a stem, which is a path
32字节，所以与今天相同。第一个31个字节定义了一个茎，这是一条路径
to this extension-level commitments. And then each, in each leaf node, we have 256 values.
对这一扩展级别的承诺。然后在每个叶节点中，每个值都有256个值。
okay so basically keys are grouped in groups of 256 values and the way that we
好的，因此基本上按键分组为256个值和我们的方式
kind of encode them in leaf nodes is with this image that I have here at the
在叶子节点中对它们进行编码，与我在这里有此图像
bottom which basically we do like a vector commitment of these elements we
底部基本上我们确实喜欢这些元素的向量承诺
to do some really tricky construction of having two vectors to really store 256 values. And the
要做一些真正棘手的构造，让两个向量真正存储256个值。和
reason for that is that, as I said before, the scalar fields are 253 bits, but unfortunately,
原因是，正如我之前所说，标量字段为253位，但不幸的是，
the values that we store are 256 bits. So, that means that we need two elements, two
我们存储的值是256位。因此，这意味着我们需要两个要素，两个
scholars per element. But that's kind of a really hairy detail, maybe. But I just wanted to explain
每个元素的学者。但这也许是一个非常毛茸茸的细节。但我只是想解释
a bit why we have two vectors to store 256 values. So, if we compare the Merkle Patricia tree with
为什么我们有两个向量存储256个值。因此，如果我们将Merkle Patricia树与
with the vertical tree and how this might affect the proof size.
使用垂直树以及这可能会影响证明大小。
So if you look at the left-hand side image, which I took from an article from Vitalik,
因此，如果您查看左侧图像，我从Vitalik的一篇文章中获取的图像，
the thing here is that despite that the branching factor is 16, you have like a semi-shallow
这里的事情是，尽管分支因素是16，但您有一个半味的
tree, you still need all the nodes data to really create a proof.
树，您仍然需要所有节点数据才能真正创建一个证明。
Because since we are using hashes, you need to verify the node bytes with the expected
因为由于我们使用了哈希，因此您需要验证带有预期的节点字节
hashes, you basically need to hash all the node data.
哈希，您基本上需要哈希所有节点数据。
That means that even if the branch in fact is 16, it means that in each node you have
这意味着即使分支实际上是16，也意味着在每个节点中
up to 16 values, which can be really big.
多达16个值，这可能很大。
In the case of vertical trees, since we are using this vector commitment, you don't really
对于垂直树，由于我们正在使用此向量承诺，因此您并不是您的确
need to provide all the vectors.
需要提供所有向量。
If you remember the verify function only required a commitment, a small proof, and the index
如果您记得验证功能，只需要承诺，一个小的证明和索引
and value that you want to prove, but not really the rest of the vector.
和您要证明的价值，但实际上并不是其余的向量。
So that is really nice, because it means that even that we are making this branching factor
所以这真的很好，因为这意味着我们正在制作这个分支因素
bigger, that doesn't really have an impact on how you can prove a single element of that
更大，这并没有真正影响您如何证明单个元素的影响
vector, or that node.
向量，或该节点。
So that's kind of at the core of why this thing works.
因此，这是为什么这件事起作用的核心。
Okay, so let's jump now to talk a bit more
好吧，所以让我们跳起来再谈更多
on how information are storing leaves of the tree.
关于信息如何存储树的叶子。
So if you remember, the leaves of the tree
因此，如果您还记得树的叶子
are vectors of 256 elements.
是256个元素的向量。
So we store the usual balance, nodes, the cold hash,
因此，我们存储通常的平衡，节点，冷哈希，
you know, like general information about the account.
您知道，就像有关帐户的一般信息。
In the case of smart contracts,
对于智能合约，
we have more space to store some extra things.
我们有更多的空间来存储一些额外的东西。
In the current EIP,
在当前的EIP中，
what we store are the first 64 storage slots
我们存储的是第一个64个存储插槽
and also the first 128 cold chunks.
还有前128个冷块。
And I will explain what a cold chunk is soon,
我会解释一下很快的冷块，
but just bear with me.
但是只要忍受我。
So, the idea is that the what we call the account header, so the leaf node that corresponds
因此，这个想法是我们所说的帐户标题，因此对应的叶子节点
to an account it has kind of the same information that we have today.
在一个帐户上，它具有与我们今天相同的信息。
In the case of smart contracts, we leverage this extra space to pack their probably information
对于智能合约，我们利用此额外的空间来包装他们的可能信息
that will be accessed, which is where the call starts, the start of the call, and the
这将被访问，这是呼叫开始的地方，呼叫的开始和
first storage slots, which are probably used with some high probability on transactions.
第一个存储插槽，可能会在交易中使用一些概率。
The rest of storage slots and the rest of call chunks are still stored, but not really
其余的存储插槽和其余的呼叫块仍然存储，但不是真的
in the lift nodes of the account.
在帐户的提升节点中。
are stored in other lift-downs. I will explain that later. So, I touched a bit here on this
存储在其他升降机中。我稍后会解释一下。所以，我在这里碰了一点
concept of cold chunks. And if you remember, on one of the first slides, I told you that the
冷块的概念。如果您还记得，在第一个幻灯片之一上，我告诉过你
execution witness, apart from balances and storage slots, it had also to include the necessary code
执行证人，除了余额和存储插槽外，还必须包括必要的代码
to validate the block. So that goes full circle here in which you should know that the contract
验证块。因此，您应该知道合同的完整圈子
code is chunked. So chunking the code is part of the process of how the code is stored in the tree.
代码是块的。因此，将代码分解是代码如何存储在树中的过程的一部分。
The way this works is that we basically group, we basically slice the contract code in 31
这种工作方式是我们基本上分组，我们基本上将合同代码切成31分。
byte groups.
字节组。
With that, we create a value of 32 bytes where the first byte is a special byte that we use
因此，我们创建了一个32个字节的值，其中第一个字节是我们使用的特殊字节
to really solve a particular problem that I will explain now in a minute.
真正解决了我现在将在一分钟内解释的特定问题。
But basically, if you look at this image, you will see that a 32-byte code chunk has
但基本上，如果您查看此图像，您会看到32字节代码块
this first special byte and then 31 bytes of the code.
第一个特殊字节，然后是代码的31个字节。
The next code chunk has this extra byte and the next 31 bytes, you do this until the end
下一个代码块具有此额外的字节和下一个31个字节，您要这样做直到结束
of the control code. So, if you also remember, there are some instructions in the EVM that
控制代码。因此，如果您还记得，EVM中有一些说明
require more than one byte. So, for example, if you do a push two instruction, that means that
需要多个字节。因此，例如，如果您执行两个指令，那意味着
or push 10 or whatever, you might find that whenever you do this chunking, there might be
或推10或其他
some bytes that are part of one chunk and there are some other bytes of the same instruction that
有些字节是一个大块的一部分，还有其他类似的字节，与
are in the next chunk so this extra byte is basically trying to signal how many bytes
在下一个块中，所以这个多余的字节基本上试图发出数字数量
from this code chunk at the start are really a continuation of a previous
从一开始，从这个代码块实际上是一个以前的延续
push x instruction in the previous chunk but it's just only that it's not really that complicated
在上一块中按X指令，但这只是并不是那么复杂
or at least more complicated than that.
或至少比这更复杂。
All right, so today, whenever you want to access some state
好吧，今天，每当您想访问某个状态时
in the tree, in the Markup Potential tree,
在树上，在标记潜在树中，
you basically use the k-check hash function
您基本上使用k-check hash函数
to calculate what is the tree key for that account, okay?
要计算该帐户的树键是什么，好吗？
For WorkPot trees, we don't use k-check,
对于工件树，我们不使用k-check，
again it's not zero-knowledge friendly
同样，这不是零知识友好的
it's not really snark friendly let's say so we're going to really use ketchak what we use is
这不是真的很友好，所以我们要真正使用凯奇克，我们使用的是
something it's kind of a an elliptical based hashing function which is called person hashing
这是一种基于椭圆形的哈希功能，称为人哈希
and it's basically explained by this kind of definition i give here i use some colors to
基本上是通过这种定义来解释的，我在这里给出了一些颜色
really help in understanding. So, the way this works is that we have a tree key function that
真正有助于理解。因此，这种工作的方法是我们有一个树密钥函数
receives the address of the account that you want to access some state. Some tree index value and
接收您要访问某种状态的帐户的地址。一些树索引值和
some subindex value. Okay? These tree index and subindex are names that you probably
一些子指数值。好的？这些树索引和子指数是您可能的名称
it doesn't make any sense to you. But hold a second there. So, the way this 3K function works
这对您没有任何意义。但是在那里握住一秒钟。因此，此3K功能的工作方式
is it is basically doing a vector commitment of a vector of size five. So, we have the first
它基本上是在做一个尺寸的向量的向量承诺。所以，我们有第一个
element is this fixed number. That has a reason, but let's just take it as a fixed number.
元素是这个固定的数字。这是有原因的，但让我们将其作为固定数字。
The next item is the most significant 16 bytes of the address.
下一个项目是地址的最重要的16个字节。
The next one is the 16 least significant bytes of the address.
下一个是地址的16个最不重要的字节。
And we do the same with the tree index here.
我们在这里对树索引也这样做。
Okay?
好的？
So this commitment give us a 32-byte value.
因此，这项承诺为我们带来了32字节的价值。
and we basically take the first 31 bytes
我们基本上采用了前31个字节
and we append the subindex, which is a single byte.
我们附加了子指数，这是一个单个字节。
So we have a 32 byte tree key, okay?
所以我们有一个32个字节树键，好吗？
So this is a very abstract function
所以这是一个非常抽象的功能
in which receive the address
收到地址的
related to the state that you want to access
与您要访问的状态有关
and these two values, okay?
这两个值，好吗？
And you kind of have the tree key.
而且您有树钥匙。
Okay, let's go, let's try to think about this
好吧，让我们走吧，让我们尝试一下
in a concrete example.
在一个具体示例中。
let's say that we want to know the tree key for the balance for an account.
假设我们想知道一个帐户平衡的树密钥。
Okay, so what you have to do is you have to use this function that we explained before.
好的，所以您要做的是您必须使用我们之前解释的此功能。
You put here the address, responding to the address that you want to know the balance.
您将地址放在这里，回应您想知道余额的地址。
You will use a tree index equal to zero, okay, this is by definition.
您将使用等于零的树索引，好的，这是定义。
And then you put here which state you want, in the case of the balance, you will have to put a one,
然后，您将想要的状态放在这里，如果是余额，则必须放置一个状态
here okay but each part uh if you see here it's kind of state of this account it's a different
在这里可以，但是每个部分嗯
subindex where the subindex is basically which index in the vector you want to access so in the
子指数基本上是您要访问的向量中哪个索引的位置
case of balance it's one uh in the case of nonce it's two and you can find this in the ip okay
平衡的情况是，在NONCE的情况下，它是两个，您可以在IP中找到它
and you do this calculation and you have the tricky and you can access that in the tree and
然后您进行此计算，并且您可以棘手，并且可以在树上访问它，
find what you want. If you remember, in the account header, we also store these special
找到想要的东西。如果您还记得，在帐户标题中，我们还存储了这些特别的
storage slots and these first cold chunks. So, if you want to access the first
存储插槽和这些第一个冷块。因此，如果您想访问第一个
storage slot zero, you basically do the same as you do here, but you put the correct index
存储插槽零，您基本上与此处相同，但是您放置了正确的索引
and the same with this special cold chunks.
这与这个特殊的冷块一样。
For the rest of the storage slots that are in the first 64
对于第一个64中的其余存储插槽
and for the rest of cold chunks that are in the first 128,
对于第一个128的其余冷块
you have to do some other calculation,
您必须进行其他计算，
which is also explained in the IP,
在IP中也解释了
which gives you the way to calculate the tree index
这为您提供了计算树索引的方法
and it's a Vindex for that storage slot.
它是该存储插槽的Vindex。
Okay, and the same with the cold chunks.
好的，冷块也一样。
Let's say that you want the cold chunk,
假设您想要冷藏
I know, 1,000.
我知道，1,000。
So it basically put 1,000 here,
因此，它基本上将1,000个
you add which it's constant,
您添加它是恒定的，
you have this chunk ID.
您有此块ID。
With that, you can calculate the tree index
这样，您可以计算树索引
and the subindex,
和子指数，
and you do the tree key function
然后您执行树密钥功能
that we explained in the previous slide,
我们在上一个幻灯片中解释了
and you get the tree key, okay?
而且您得到了树钥匙，好吗？
This is like maybe the part that is a bit more complex and it might take some minutes
这可能是更复杂的部分，可能需要几分钟
to digest it, digest this, so if it sounds confusing, don't be worried.
要消化它，请消化它，因此，如果听起来令人困惑，请不要担心。
Just try to come back to this slide later and hopefully it will make some sense.
只需尝试稍后再回到这张幻灯片，希望这将是有道理的。
The main idea of adding this constants for storage slots and cold chunks is basically
将此常数添加到存储插槽和冷块的主要思想基本上是
a way of partitioning the address space for this address so these both don't overlap,
一种分区此地址的地址空间的方法，这样俩都不会重叠，
okay? Because this is really a big number that basically makes these three indexes
好的？因为这实际上是一个很大的数字，基本上是这三个索引
not really overlap for storage slots and cold chunks.
储存插槽和冷​​块并没有真正重叠。
Okay, so now we will switch topics a bit and talk about gas accounting. I think that
好的，所以现在我们将稍微切换主题并谈论气体会计。我认为
Guillaume is here, maybe he wants to continue.
Guillaume在这里，也许他想继续。
Yeah, I don't know if you guys can hear me.
是的，我不知道你们是否能听到我的声音。
Yeah, we can hear you, but maybe before we switch topics here,
是的，我们可以听到您的声音，但是也许在我们在这里切换主题之前，
a couple questions in the chat here that might be...
这里的聊天中有几个问题，可能是...
Sorry, before we get to the questions,
抱歉，在我们解决问题之前，
I just had one comment to give to the previous slide.
我只是发表了一条评论，可以给上一张幻灯片。
Sure, great.
当然，太好了。
Yeah, it's just that, yeah,
是的，只是，是的，
domain storage offset is really big,
域存储偏移确实很大，
but on top of that, the code size itself is limited.
但最重要的是，代码大小本身是有限的。
we want to increase the size of the code,
我们想增加代码的大小，
but we will never increase it to the size of main storage
但是我们永远不会将其增加到主存储的大小
offset.
抵消。
Well, there should never be a clash, basically.
好吧，基本上永远不应该发生冲突。
Got it.
知道了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Would you be willing to walk through quickly
你愿意迅速穿过吗
how retrieval changes with Merkle trees
默克尔树的检索如何变化
compared to Merkle trees?
与默克尔树相比？
question is like what's the benefit of calculating the extra commitments
问题就像计算额外承诺有什么好处
uh you may like the performance overhead of burkle trees compared to markup potential trees
嗯，您可能喜欢伯克树的性能与标记潜在树相比
i believe so when yeah when you're when you're retrieving data right so um burkle tree the kind
我相信，当您正确检索数据时，当您正确地检索数据时，嗯
of cryptography using Broker Tweez is much heavier than doing hashes. So, doing hashes
使用经纪人Tweez的密码学比进行哈希重得多。所以，做哈希
in CPUs is really, really, really, really fast. Unfortunately, doing elliptical operations is much
在CPU中确实非常非常快，非常非常快。不幸的是，进行椭圆操作很多
slower. This is basically a trade-off of trying to make the cryptography of Broker Tweez be really
慢点。基本上，这是试图使经纪人的加密术的权衡取舍
friendly for snarks. So it's basically a trade-off. We have done a lot of work to make all this
友好的蛇。因此，这基本上是一个权衡。我们已经做了很多工作来制造这一切
cryptography implementation as fast as possible. But even if we do try to do the best thing
加密实施尽可能快。但是，即使我们确实尝试做最好的事情
possible it will never be as fast as the Merkle Patricia tree kind of cryptography.
它可能永远不会像默克尔·帕特里夏（Merkle Patricia）树那样快。
So it's basically a decided trade-off.
因此，这基本上是一个决定的权衡。
We kind of gained some benefits, but we have to pay some costs.
我们有一些好处，但我们必须支付一些费用。
Cool, that makes sense.
酷，这很有意义。
Mario, any other questions you want to surface now while we're here?
马里奥，当我们在这里时，您现在还想遇到其他问题吗？
There was a question whether the Verkult tree implementation will have a hiding property
有一个疑问，Verkult树实施是否具有隐藏属性
yes commitments uh hiding whether it applies here uh no it it's only having uh binding properties
是的承诺是否隐藏在这里是否适用，uh u n o n o n u n n uk n us taking uh binding属性
not really hiding uh because hiding doesn't make sense since all this the state is public anyway
并不是真的隐藏UH，因为隐藏没有意义，因为这一切国家都是公开的
so the commitment doesn't really require to avoid leaking information or or similar um
因此，承诺并不需要避免泄漏信息或或类似的UM
right it's a really good question yeah yeah it makes sense yeah thank you um yeah i think we can
是的，是的，是的，是的，是的，是的，谢谢，是的，我想我们可以
move on for now. Guillaume? Yeah, I don't know, can I share my screen? I don't know if it's gonna work.
现在继续前进。 Guillaume？是的，我不知道，我可以分享我的屏幕吗？我不知道它是否会起作用。
Yeah go ahead, you have the present button right here. Share screen, okay so I guess it's going to
是的，您在这里有现在的按钮。共享屏幕，好的，我想它会去
share my entire screen Wow you can also upload a presentation or I mean it's it's the same
分享我的整个屏幕哇，您也可以上传演示文稿，或者我的意思是它是一样的
presentation it's just that my screen might be a bit too large for it for the entire okay let me
演示只是我的屏幕可能太大了，因为整个好吧，让我
try. You'll tell me if it works or not. Here we go. Oh, okay. Here we go. All right. Does that work?
尝试。您会告诉我它是否有效。开始了。哦好的。开始了。好的。那起作用吗？
Yes. Yes. Perfect.
是的。是的。完美的。
it. So I'm going to talk about the gas changes, because we change, well, we make pretty heavy
它。所以我要谈论气体变化，因为我们改变了，好吧，我们变得非常沉重
changes to the data model, it should be obvious. So the question is, how do we update the gas
更改数据模型，应该很明显。所以问题是，我们如何更新气体
model to reflect this? And the first intuition to have is that we are no longer trying to
反映这一点的模型？而第一个拥有的直觉是，我们不再试图
reduce the amount of IO, right? We are no longer trying to reduce the growth of the state size,
减少IO的量，对吗？我们不再试图减少状态规模的增长，
or at least more accurately, it's not that we're not trying to make this happen,
或至少更准确地说，这并不是说我们不是要实现这一目标，而是
to prevent this. It's not our primary focus. Our primary focus is to make the witness that
为了防止这种情况。这不是我们的主要重点。我们的主要重点是让证人
Stakeless clients download and unpack and execute as small as possible.
毫无根据的客户下载并解开包装和执行尽可能小。
Then, of course, if on top of that, we can, you know,
当然，如果最重要的话，我们知道，我们可以
stamp the state growth and ensure speedy IO, that's better.
标记状态增长并确保快速的IO，这更好。
But that's not the primary concern anymore.
但这不再是主要问题。
So, yeah, what we are looking at is making sure that
所以，是的，我们正在寻找的是确保
we reduce, yeah, we look at all the actions
是的，我们减少了所有的动作
that will increase the witness size,
这会增加证人的规模
like reading the state.
喜欢阅读状态。
Every time you read the state,
每次阅读状态时，
you need to prove that what you read was there
您需要证明您阅读的内容在那里
and contained the value that you claim it contained.
并包含您声称包含的价值。
So you will need to add it to the witness,
因此，您需要将其添加到证人中，
so you will need to add it to the block,
因此，您需要将其添加到块中，
so you need to prove it.
因此，您需要证明这一点。
So that's an action that will have a gas impact,
因此，这是一种会产生气体影响的动作，
that will have a gas cost.
那将有天然气成本。
Same thing with writing to the state
写信给国家同样的事情
because you write to the state
因为你写信给国家
so that there's an update of the root commitments.
这样可以更新根承诺。
So you need to somehow,
所以你需要以某种方式
well, first of all, you need to pay for this update
好吧，首先，您需要为此更新付费
so that you don't frivolously keep writing data
这样您就不会轻易地继续编写数据
that will increase the amount of calculation
这将增加计算量
without paying for it.
不付钱。
And one thing, I mean, Ignacio already mentioned,
一件事，我的意思是，伊格纳西奥已经提到过，
like now the code is very much part of the tree.
像现在一样，代码是树的一部分。
And that's because when we execute code,
那是因为当我们执行代码时，
we need to prove that the code we execute
我们需要证明我们执行的代码
was also part of the state,
也是国家的一部分，
that we don't execute some random code
我们不执行一些随机代码
that comes from nowhere.
那是来自无处的。
So, we need to also change the guest model to account for what gets executed, because
因此，我们还需要更改来宾模型以说明执行的内容，因为
what gets executed is added to the witness, and will make the witness bigger, and therefore
被执行的是添加到证人中，并将使证人更大，因此
the block bigger.
块更大。
So, there are really five cost changes.
因此，实际上有五个成本变化。
One thing that I should say first is that making the distinction of what has already
我首先要说的一件事是使已经有什么区别
been accessed as opposed to what has not been accessed is something that already exists
已经访问而不是访问的是已经存在的东西
in the current state model with the access list.
在当前状态模型中，带有访问列表。
So we want to reuse this scheme of access list because once something has been added
因此，我们要重复使用此访问列表方案，因为一旦添加了东西
to the witness, the witness no longer grows.
对证人来说，证人不再成长。
So it's only the first time that the hefty cost has to be paid.
因此，这只是第一次必须支付高昂的成本。
But once it has been added to the witness, it's just a matter of reading from memory
但是一旦将其添加到证人中，这只是记忆中阅读的问题
cache.
缓存。
So we have a model that already exists in Ethereum right now.
因此，我们有一个现已存在于以太坊中的模型。
It's called the access list.
它称为访问列表。
And so we basically take the same model and we change the costs.
因此，我们基本上采用相同的模型，然后改变成本。
Except that we take some of the model of the new tree, right?
除了我们采用新树的一些模型，对吗？
If you remember, we have this way of calculating where a value goes in the tree.
如果您还记得，我们有这种计算树中值的位置。
and the idea is because the vertical node width is 256
这个想法是因为垂直节点宽度为256
it's basically the last bytes
基本上是最后一个字节
all the values that are grouped in the same
所有分组的值
256 chunk will be
256块将是
next to one another and so every time
彼此旁边，每次
what we want to do is every time we access one of those groups
我们要做的是每次我们访问其中一个小组
we will pay a cost, like a hefty cost, but then every
我们将付费，例如巨额成本，但每一次
individual leaf in the group will be much cheaper to access for the first time and even cheaper to
小组中的个人叶子首次可以便宜得多，甚至更便宜
access for the second time. And another concern that I didn't talk about, by the way, until now,
第二次访问。到目前为止，我还没有谈论的另一个问题，直到现在
is that yes, we want to fit the guest model to the new storage model. But at the same time,
是的，我们希望将访客模型适合新的存储模型。但与此同时
we don't want to break every single application out there that might have tried to optimize for
我们不想打破可能尝试优化的每个应用程序
a given gas model. So everything, all those values, they might seem random, but they've
给定的气体模型。因此，所有这些价值观，它们似乎都是随机的，但是它们已经
actually been thought to more or less change nothing from the gas consumption perspective,
实际上，从气体消耗角度来看，或多或少任何变化都没有改变，
from the EVM perspective. From the client perspective, it's completely different.
从EVM的角度来看。从客户的角度来看，这是完全不同的。
But from the DAP perspective, it's fairly similar. It's not perfect, but it's pretty close.
但是从DAP的角度来看，它相当相似。它不是完美的，但是很近。
Yeah, so the idea is that we just get rid of all the old cold storage costs that we used to have
是的，所以想法是我们摆脱了过去的所有旧冷藏成本
with access list and we replace them with this model.
使用访问列表，我们将其替换为此模型。
So yeah, what are the events that trigger those costs?
是的，触发这些费用的事件是什么？
Well, there's every time you access the state itself,
好吧，每当您访问州本身时，
so if you store, if you load,
因此，如果您存储，如果您加载，
but now if you check the balance,
但是现在，如果您检查余额，
that also means that you have to go into the tree.
这也意味着您必须进入树。
I mean, okay, admittedly,
我的意思是，好的，诚然，
That's what you already had to do, so it doesn't really change much in this respect.
这就是您已经要做的，因此在这方面并没有太大变化。
But yeah, so rephrasing what I should have said, every time you access the state,
但是，是的，所以每次您访问州时，我应该说的话，
you, like with a balance, with a self-destruct, with a code copy, you will incur those costs.
您就像保持平衡，具有自我毁灭，使用代码副本一样，您将产生这些费用。
One thing that changes is that we do not charge the cost for withdrawals.
改变的一件事是，我们不收取提款费用。
Withdrawals need to be added.
需要添加提款。
For example, I'm saying withdrawals, but also the Denkun beacon block root precompile.
例如，我说取款，但也说denkun信标块根的预编译。
Actually, system contract, sorry.
实际上，系统合同，对不起。
all those values are added to the witness but no one pays for it for them so those costs don't get
所有这些价值都添加到证人中，但没有人为他们付费，所以这些费用不会得到
charged um and it's the same thing because you pay an upfront cost of 21 000 gas to send a
收费UM，这是同一回事，因为您支付了21 000燃气的前期费用来发送
transaction we do not uh charge those costs for uh for sending and for the sender and the recipient
交易，我们不向UH收取这些费用，以发送和发送者和收件人
of the transaction but everything else is um is charged including like we said contract code
交易中的一切，但其他所有内容都被收取，包括我们说的合同代码
Um, we, yeah, like, like I said before, you only charge, uh, the first time, right?
嗯，是的，就像我之前说过的那样，您只收费，嗯，第一次，对吗？
Because then, uh, the, the damage is done.
因为那样，嗯，损坏就造成了。
You added data to the, to the, to the witness.
您将数据添加到证人中。
So then it becomes, uh, the warm access costs, which is like the cost of reading from memory
因此，它变成了温暖的访问成本，就像从记忆中阅读的成本一样
and not loading from disk or, uh, uh, or, uh, any other operations like this.
并且不从磁盘或，呃，呃，或者，呃，任何其他类似的操作加载。
So, right, so basically, I don't know if Inacio had in mind to take over here, but I can continue.
因此，是的，基本上，我不知道Inacio是否想在这里接管，但是我可以继续。
I'll take it as yes.
我认为是的。
So yeah, you have this new gas accounting, you have all new crypto, all new tree formats,
是的，您有这个新的气体会计，您拥有所有新的加密货币，所有新的树格式，
all new protocols.
所有新协议。
Is this the end of it?
这是终点吗？
No.
不。
Because we need to convert the state.
因为我们需要转换状态。
We have a state in an mpt format.
我们具有MPT格式的状态。
There's like a billion leaves.
有十亿个叶子。
So that's like 200, okay, more like 300 gigabytes by now.
这就是200，好吧，现在更像300千兆字节。
Or at least by the time we expect to have to start using vertical trees.
或至少到我们期望开始使用垂直树时。
So we have to somehow convert everything.
因此，我们必须以某种方式转换一切。
it's not that easy because we have to, because we use a different hashing model to store
这并不容易，因为我们必须这样做，因为我们使用不同的哈希模型来存储
data in the tree, we have to rehash everything. And we've been looking at several strategies,
树上的数据，我们必须重新进行所有内容。我们一直在研究几种策略，
some of them were more centralized, others are really decentralized but pretty heavy
其中一些人更加集中，有些人确实是分散的，但很重
on the computation. And we settled on the overlay tree, which is a method where you, yeah, so you
在计算上。我们定居在覆盖树上，这是您的方法，是的，所以您
start at block, just before the fork, you start with an mpt tree, right? And everything that is,
从叉子开始，就在叉子之前，您从MPT树开始，对吗？以及一切
I'm not sure how to call it, like green-blue are values that were written to the state before the
我不确定如何称呼它，就像绿蓝色是在
fork and everything that is purple is our values that get written to the state after the fork so
叉子和紫色的一切都是我们的价值观，在叉子之后被写入州
currently we are just before the fork so there are no purple values and we have this iterator
目前，我们就在叉子之前，所以没有紫色值，我们有这个迭代器
that is going to sweep the state over time like it's going to the stride of the iterator is
随着时间的流逝，它会像迭代器的大步一样
a given value that is chosen so that most of the nodes or at least your average node can follow
选择的给定值，以便大多数节点或至少您的平均节点可以遵循
can copy so many leaves per block without missing the slot, so being able to follow the network.
可以复制每个块的叶子很多，而不会缺少插槽，因此能够跟随网络。
And those weird red triangles represent, by the way, I forgot to mention that,
顺便说一句，那些怪异的红色三角形代表了，我忘了提到
the internal nodes of the MPD tree. So the red triangles are the internal nodes,
MPD树的内部节点。因此，红色三角形是内部节点，
and the blue-green squares are the leaves.
蓝绿色的正方形是叶子。
So when the fork happens,
因此，当叉子发生时，
we start with a fresh vertical route
我们从新的垂直路线开始
that is considered as,
被认为是
in an abstract way,
以抽象的方式
it's laid over the mpg tree.
它放在MPG树上。
And this new vertical route
这条新的垂直路线
is where all the writes will end up.
就是所有写作最终的地方。
So if you write a new value to the tree,
因此，如果您为树编写新值，
it's a purple value it will end up in the overlay vertical tree now what if you uh oh yeah and on
这是一个紫色的价值，它最终将在覆盖垂直树上，如果你嗯，哦，是的，
top of that every block the the iterator moves by n value so here n equals two so yeah the green
最重要的是每个块迭代器移动n值，所以在这里n等于两个，所以绿色
the green arrow represents the head of the iterator and it sweeped two leaves that got
绿色箭头代表迭代器的头部，它扫了两片叶子
moved or more exactly copied into the vertical tree and now if i want to look for the
移动或更精确地复制到垂直树中，现在我想寻找
to the pink square, which is currently in the Merkle tree,
到目前在默克尔树上的粉红色广场，
what we do is that we first try to read
我们要做的是我们第一次尝试阅读
from the Virkle tree, we do not find it there.
从virkle树中，我们在那里找不到。
So we go to the Merkle tree, which is read only,
因此，我们去默克尔树，只读，
and we find it there.
我们在那里找到它。
And we continue this way, so the iterator at each block,
我们继续这样，因此每个块的迭代器，
the iterator continues copying values,
迭代器继续复制值，
and you can see that, for example,
例如，您可以看到
one value that used to be in the MPT has been clobbered,
过去在MPT中的一个值已被凝结，
has been, sorry it hasn't been clobbered,
对不起，它没有被撞倒，
it's a value that was copied for the MPT
这是为MPT复制的价值
but it has been overwritten,
但是它被覆盖了，
so the MPT is frozen it doesn't change,
因此，MPT冻结了，它不会改变，
but the values themselves keep getting copied
但是价值观本身不断复制
unless of course they overwrite a new version of that value.
当然，除非他们覆盖该值的新版本。
And eventually, or at least when the fork block has been finalized, you can afford to delete all the mpt internal nodes.
最终，或者至少在确定叉子块时，您有能力删除所有MPT内部节点。
So you're freeing a lot of space.
因此，您可以释放很多空间。
And I'm sorry, I don't know what happened with the slide, with the formatting here.
很抱歉，我不知道幻灯片发生了什么，并在这里格式化。
But the idea is that when all the leaves, because the iterator keeps progressing, eventually, and because the iterator keeps progressing and the MPT itself is read-only, eventually, all the nodes will be, all the leaves will have been moved to the vertical tree.
但是，想法是，当所有叶子（因为迭代器都不断进步时垂直树。
So you can afford to delete all the internal data.
因此，您有能力删除所有内部数据。
And one thing, like this model is a bit simplified, so I did not really represent that on those slides.
还有一件事，就像这个模型有点简化，所以我并没有在这些幻灯片上真正代表它。
But what you have to know is that currently I represent the leaves in the MPT and the
但是您要知道的是，目前我代表MPT和
vertical tree as being in the same order, but they're not.
垂直树的顺序相同，但不是。
This is just a simplification.
这只是一个简化。
So yeah, this is the gist of the method.
是的，这是该方法的要旨。
The question is, how do we set the stride of the iterator?
问题是，我们如何设定迭代器的大步？
And we have a bit of a model.
我们有一些模型。
And basically it looks like we can afford,
基本上看来我们负担得起，
what we want is to,
我们想要的是
it's a trade-off between how many leaves we copy per block
这是我们复制多少叶子之间的权衡
and how many machines,
以及多少个机器
what part of the network we are comfortable with losing
我们对丢失的网络的哪一部分
during the transition.
在过渡期间。
Of course, we cannot afford to lose more than one third
当然，我们不能损失超过三分之一
of the network.
网络。
That would be critical.
那将是至关重要的。
But we can see that already with 5,000 leaves, we're definitely not losing too many.
但是我们可以看到，已经有5,000片叶子，我们绝对不会损失太多。
We can afford to lose more than 20% of the network and still complete the transition in two months.
我们有能力损失超过20％的网络，并在两个月内完成过渡。
So I think by now, given the test we've done,
所以我认为，鉴于我们已经完成了测试，
we're pretty comfortable doing 10,000 leaves per block.
我们很自在地每块做10,000片叶子。
So we would be able to proceed with the conversion within 15 days,
因此，我们可以在15天内进行转换，
which is not too bad.
这还不错。
But yeah, ultimately, we need to do more testing.
但是，是的，最终，我们需要进行更多测试。
We might even discover that 20,000 leaves is okay
我们甚至可能发现20,000片叶子还可以
because as we go more,
因为随着我们的发展
the machines connected to the network
连接到网络的机器
are more and more powerful.
越来越强大。
But yeah, this is still,
但是，是的，这仍然是
this is not exactly an open question,
这不是一个悬而未决的问题，
but it's still a parameter
但这仍然是一个参数
that can change before the fork.
在叉子之前可以改变。
Right.
正确的。
So once again, Ignacio,
因此，再次，Ignacio，
I don't know if you plan to talk about this,
我不知道您是否打算谈论这个，
but I can do it.
但是我可以做到。
Okay.
好的。
So like I said,
所以就像我说的，
Sorry.
对不起。
Yep.
是的。
Hello?
你好？
Okay, I'll continue.
好吧，我继续。
So, like I said, we have to rehash everything.
因此，就像我说的那样，我们必须重新重新进行所有内容。
But the problem is that so far,
但是问题是到目前为止
not everybody has stored,
不是每个人都存储了，
In fact, a very, very small majority of people have stored pre-images of all the key hashes in their databases.
实际上，大多数人都非常非常少，在其数据库中存储了所有关键哈希的前图。
It's like 70 gigabytes, more or less.
就像70 GB，或多或少。
So, yeah, why would you take up 70 gigabytes if you don't have to?
所以，是的，如果不需要的话，为什么要拿70千兆字节？
The problem is that for the transition, you have to.
问题在于，您必须进行过渡。
You have to have them.
你必须有它们。
So we don't really – we have to find a way to distribute those pre-images.
因此，我们并不是真的 - 我们必须找到一种分发这些前图像的方法。
And to do this, we have looked at several steps, several methods, but the fact is that
为此，我们研究了几个步骤，几种方法，但事实是
Erdogan and Reff store their data by pre-images, so they have the ability to generate a file
Erdogan和REFF通过前图片存储数据，因此他们有能力生成文件
that it could then distribute.
然后可以分发。
And it's not as bad as, for example, converting the entire database
而且它并不像转换整个数据库那样糟糕
because the entire database is very large.
因为整个数据库非常大。
The verification, if you are given the pre-images,
验证，如果您获得了前图，
you can go over your own database and verify that you've got all the pre-images.
您可以浏览自己的数据库，并验证您是否拥有所有前图。
So it's much cheaper and much safer to distribute.
因此，它便宜得多，而且更安全。
But the consequence would be that you cannot exactly start the sweep right away.
但是结果是您不能立即开始扫荡。
You need to have some time to get the pre-images generated,
您需要有一些时间才能生成前图像，
like the pre-images of the frozen Merkle tree, distributed.
就像冻结的默克尔树的前图像一样。
So we would give ourselves a month, sorry, not a month, a week,
因此，我们会给自己一个月，对不起，不是一个月，一个星期，
during which the vocal tree gets written to,
在此期间，人声将其写入
but no conversion happens.
但是没有发生转换。
So we still have the two trees.
所以我们仍然有两棵树。
And when a client receives the pre-images,
当客户收到前图像时，
it can very easily verify
它很容易验证
that it's got all the pre-images it needs
它有所有需要的前图
because it's only the pre-images of a frozen vocal tree.
因为这只是冷冻声带的前图像。
And then the sweeping star.
然后是扫星星。
And if we find, of course,
当然，如果我们发现
that there's a problem in the pre-image distribution,
图像前分布有问题，
We can always make an emergency release.
我们总是可以进行紧急发布。
It's not really great, but it's,
它不是很棒，但是是
at least we have a way to handle that.
至少我们有办法处理这一点。
But yeah, it's still kind of an open problem,
但是，是的，这仍然是一个空旷的问题，
but it's not a, doesn't feel like a big one.
但这不是一个，并不像个大。
So we're not losing sleep over this one.
因此，我们不会因为这个人而失去睡眠。
And then the last thing I plan to talk about
然后我打算谈论的最后一件事
was how we sync.
是我们同步的方式。
So currently, there's only one client
所以目前，只有一个客户
that has sync implemented,
已经实施了同步
which is a Verkle version of SnapSync.
这是Snapsync的Verkle版本。
But what I want to give you is an overview
但是我想给你的是概述
of what you could do with Verkle trees,
您可以用Verkle树做什么，
how Verkle trees would simplify the sync.
Verkle树如何简化同步。
And the idea is that you already have parts of the tree
这个想法是您已经有了树的一部分
packaged in every block.
包装在每个街区。
so the idea is to leverage this fact
所以这个想法是利用这一事实
this feature to solve the sync
解决同步的功能
and make sync much simpler
并使同步更简单
so you would start at block end
因此，您将从块端开始
the block you join the network at
您加入网络的块
and you execute statelessly
然后您无情地执行
but as you go you keep rebuilding trees
但是当你走时，你不断重建树木
so you can actually accumulate all the leaves
因此您实际上可以积累所有叶子
and you know you have the latest version of a leaf
而且您知道您有最新版本的叶子
which is always the biggest problem
这始终是最大的问题
with the sync because, yeah,
使用同步是因为，是的，
you are given the latest view of the tree.
为您提供了树的最新视图。
So if a leaf hasn't been touched,
因此，如果叶子没有被触摸，
it means you have the latest version.
这意味着您有最新版本。
Simply it's from a previous block.
只是来自以前的块。
And then what you do in the background
然后您在后台做什么
is you start downloading,
您是开始下载吗，
you start asking nodes around you,
您开始询问周围的节点，
full nodes around you for all the leaves
所有叶子周围的完整节点
that have not been seen in the stateless view so far.
到目前为止，在无状态的观点中尚未看到。
And you can verify them very, very easily
您可以非常非常轻松地验证它们
because it's only,
因为只是
every time it's only gonna be a small subset of the tree.
每次只会是树的一小部分。
So you can recompute the root commitment very, very fast,
因此，您可以非常非常快地重新计算根本承诺，
at least comparatively fast
至少快速
and verify that what you've got is the current state,
并验证您所拥有的是当前状态，
at least fits in your current view.
至少适合您当前的视图。
and once again
再一次
it doesn't even matter how long this process
这个过程甚至都没关系
lasts because you can keep executing blocks
持续，因为您可以继续执行块
statelessly
无国籍
until that point
直到那时
so yeah, that's
是的，那是
pretty much the idea I think
我想的几乎
that was, yeah
是的
Ignacio, I'll let you conclude
伊格纳西奥，我让你得出结论
can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
yep, okay
是的，好吧
because I had a problem with my mic.
因为我的麦克风有问题。
Yeah, this is kind of the end of the presentation.
是的，这是演讲的结尾。
I left here an image on like why we use an elephant
我在这里留下了一个图像，就像我们为什么使用大象
for Virgo trees, which might be surprising
对于处女座树，这可能令人惊讶
or not really obvious.
或不是很明显。
So I learned from Guillaume that the elephants are known
所以我从纪前学到了大象是已知的
for destroying branches of tree or uprooting trees,
为了摧毁树木或连根拔起树的树枝，
which really is pretty related with what we are trying to do
这确实与我们试图做的事情相关
for the Ethereum protocol, of changing the MarkupObsidia
对于以太坊协议，更改Markupobsidia
tree with another tree.
树与另一棵树。
So I think this elephant kind of mascot
所以我认为这种大象是吉祥物
was a really good idea from, I think,
我认为是一个很好的主意
Guillaume and Pari from the DevOps team.
Devops团队的Guillaume和Pari。
So it was totally Pari.
所以这完全是pari。
Well, yeah, great to him.
好吧，是的，对他很棒。
And I think that maybe Sosh wants to say something else.
而且我认为也许Sosh想说其他话。
Yeah, just really quick, thank you
是的，真的很快，谢谢
to uh ignacio guillaume everyone here uh ignacio and guillaume just wanted to emphasize that
uh Ignacio Guillaume这里的每个人UH Ignacio和Guillaume只是想强调
they've been doing a lot of heavy lifting on vertical for a long time so a lot of appreciation
他们已经在垂直方面做了很多繁重的工作，所以很高兴
to their work and many others who are working on vertical i'm here happy just to play a small part
他们的工作以及许多在垂直工作的人，我在这里很高兴扮演一小部分
and also for anyone interested uh we have bi-weekly vertical implementer calls anyone is
对于任何感兴趣的人，我们都有每两周一次的垂直实施者打电话
welcome to listen in of course if you want to take a more active role um feel free to drop a message
当然，如果您想扮演更积极的角色，请欢迎聆听
in the ethereum r d discord there should be a link handy um but yes bi-weekly calls where we
在以太坊r d和不和谐中，应该有一个方便的链接，但是的，每两周打电话
continue these kinds of discussions awesome thank you so much guys um uh very well i think we can
继续这类讨论，真是太好了，非常感谢，我认为我们可以
conclude the presentation let me see if there are any questions for you before we rip up um yeah
结束演示文稿让我看看我们是否有任何疑问，然后我们撕毁嗯
thank you so much uh all three of you uh it was really great uh ignacio especially and with uh
非常感谢你们这三个嗯，嗯，这真是太好了
all the deep down photography and uh guillaume the glass pricing with uh the migration thanks
所有深处的摄影和uh guillaume玻璃价格与移民表示感谢
so much it's uh it's a lot to digest but uh i believe it might be some questions um
太多了，这是很多要消化的，但是我相信这可能是一些问题
One thing which was asked before was about the post-quantum security, whether Verkl improves
以前询问的一件事是关于量子后的安全性，Verkl是否有所改善
in the situation, whether it's makes it maybe easier in the future to swap for something
在这种情况下，是否会使将来更容易交换某物
quantum secure.
量子安全。
Yeah, so the reality as we discussed there in the chat is all the elliptic core-based
是的，所以我们在聊天中讨论的现实是所有基于椭圆的核心
cryptography isn't really safe for like quantum computers. So actually we have yes, I mean
对于量子计算机而言，加密并不是安全的。所以实际上我们有，我的意思是
vertical tree cryptography isn't safe for quantum, so that's period. But we also have
对于量子，垂直树密码学不是安全的，所以这是时期。但是我们也有
to do all our kind of changes in the protocol, like the signatures that we use for transactions
在协议中进行所有类型的更改，例如我们用于交易的签名
is elliptic curve based, so we will have to change the way that signatures work. KCG commitments
是基于椭圆曲线的，因此我们必须改变签名的工作方式。 KCG承诺
you're seeing blobs or so you say it will be curve-based cryptography, so that will
您正在看到斑点，或者您说这将是基于曲线的密码学，所以
also break.
也打破。
So usually the plan that the way that we think about cryptography and this problem is every
因此，通常我们会以我们对密码学和这个问题的看法的计划是每个计划
cryptography using the protocol should have a candidate that is quantum safe.
使用该协议的密码学应具有量子安全的候选者。
And any new cryptography that we plan to use or introduce now should have an alternative
现在我们计划使用或介绍的任何新密码学都应有替代方案
that we can change in the future.
我们将来可以改变。
The thing with this is that this quantum cryptography is usually pretty new, at least compared to
这样做的是，这个量子密码学通常是非常新的，至少与
the more solid cryptography that we use now, and also it's much slower and has other trade-offs
我们现在使用的更稳定的密码学，而且还要慢得多，并且还有其他权衡
like bigger signatures or things like that.
像更大的签名或类似的东西。
So it's not really like a simple choice to say, hey, just simply use quantum-safe cryptography
因此，这并不是一个简单的选择，嘿，只需使用量子安全加密
that has other trade-offs that will impact UX or have other, you know, effects that will
还有其他权衡会影响UX或具有其他效果的其他权衡
be pretty bad.
很糟糕。
So whenever this risk becomes really closer to being practical, let's say, then we will
因此，每当这种风险变得更接近实用时，假设我们，我们就会
should really start switching this kind of unsafe cryptography
应该真正开始切换这种不安全的加密
to other schemes.
到其他方案。
ALEXANDRE DROUINIAS- Right, but that's the point.
Alexandre Drouinias-对，但这是重点。
The work we do now might have to be redone,
我们现在所做的工作可能必须重做，
but at least we'll have done it once,
但是至少我们会做一次，
so we'll understand what's going on.
因此，我们将了解发生了什么。
And yeah, currently it makes complete sense
是的，目前完全有道理
to focus on elliptic curves, because, well, first of all,
专注于椭圆曲线，因为首先，
it still remains to be proven
仍然有待证明
that quantum computing is really around the corner.
该量子计算确实在拐角处。
And that's more importantly
这更重要
that they can break elliptic curve cryptography.
它们可以打破椭圆曲线密码学。
But when this happens,
但是当这种情况发生时
we'll be ready to switch again.
我们将准备再次切换。
Yeah, awesome.
是的，很棒。
Yeah, it makes sense.
是的，这很有意义。
I think so much to both of you.
我对你们俩都这么多。
The question on the computational overhead, it's two questions here, but maybe we can
关于计算开销的问题，这里是两个问题，但也许我们可以
merge them.
合并他们。
So, MPTs have a branching factor of 16, while welcome trees have 256 order-running benchmarks,
因此，MPT的分支系数为16，而受欢迎的树有256个基准，
links, or analysis on tradeoffs for bandwidth computation.
链接或对带宽计算的权衡分析。
And another question around the computation is on the transition, on the node transitioning
围绕计算的另一个问题是在节点过渡上的过渡
to the Virchow tree, how much heavier machine is it for this?
对于Virchow树，这是多少重的机器？
Yeah, so regarding the branching factor question, so the special, like where the magic happens
是的，关于分支因素问题，所以特殊，例如魔术发生的地方
for Broca trees is that the branching factor don't have a, doesn't have an impact on these
因为broca树是分支因素没有一个，对这些没有影响
openings that we have to do on each node or on each vector. There's still a trade-off there
我们必须在每个节点或每个向量上进行的开口。那里仍然有一个权衡
because the branching factor, so in any Broca arguments, the proof size and the verification
因为分支因素，因此在任何Broca参数中，证明大小和验证
time, the verification time is linear on the size of the vector. So we cannot really like simply
时间，验证时间是在向量的大小上线性的。所以我们真的不能简单地喜欢
select a branching factor of 1 million and store everything in a single vector.
选择100万个分支系数，然后将所有内容存储在单个矢量中。
So there still has to be a balance between the branching factor and the cost of doing
因此，分支因素和做成本之间仍然必须保持平衡
openings for verifying openings for verifiers.
用于验证验证者开口的开口。
So yeah.
是的。
And from another perspective, increasing the branching factor makes it more shadow-aware.
从另一个角度来看，增加分支因素使其更加阴影感。
So that requires less elements in the proof.
因此，这需要更少的证明元素。
So yeah, you have to do some kind of multi-factor analysis on verifying time for proofs and
是的，您必须在验证证明时间和
how much that helps the depth of the tree and things like that.
多少帮助树的深度以及类似的事物。
So yeah.
是的。
I don't know, maybe the other question regarding state conversion.
我不知道，也许还有关于状态conversion依的另一个问题。
So maybe Guillaume wants to complement this later, but we have done some benchmarks on
因此，也许Guillaume希望稍后再补充，但是我们已经做了一些基准
usual desktop machines and also Rock 5B as a lower, lowest setup hardware.
通常的台式机和摇滚5B作为较低，最低的设置硬件。
And I think that we feel comfortable around migrating probably 10K key values per block,
而且我认为我们对每个块迁移可能10k键值感到舒适，
in a Rock 5e, but the benchmark that we did at that point in time didn't include 4844
在岩石5e中，但是我们当时所做的基准不包括4844
load in mainnet because it didn't exist.
在主网中加载，因为它不存在。
So probably we'll have to do some new benchmarks to really understand how the current mainnet
因此，也许我们必须进行一些新的基准，以真正了解当前的主网
load um how much like performance performance or like resource like it it leaves to really
加载um多么喜欢性能性能或喜欢的资源
add this extra work of doing the conversion per block uh or even decide if rock 5b or this really
添加此额外的工作来进行每个块uh的转换，甚至决定是否真的是岩石5B或这是否真的
low setup machines are really uh are reasonable expectations for nose to be really brand this
低设置机器真的是对鼻子的合理期望
conversion i don't know if guilliams want to say something more uh no that was pretty much it
conversion依我不知道吉利亚姆是否想说更多的话
I seem to have understood that it was a bandwidth question.
我似乎已经知道这是一个带宽问题。
So the point is that, yeah,
所以关键是，是的，
it's the average size for the proof is 150 kilobytes.
这是证明的平均大小为150千容器。
So we're doing way worse than that with blobs.
因此，我们的情况比斑点更糟。
So we don't really, I mean,
所以我们不是真的，我的意思是
we haven't really done any benchmarks to this,
我们还没有真正对此做任何基准，
but that's because we don't expect it's nothing.
但这是因为我们不期望什么都没有。
so it's it's not really uh we don't expect any any issue with that
所以这不是真的，我们没有任何问题
uh that's interesting uh thank you so much i was i was wondering how it will look like
嗯，很有趣的嗯，谢谢你，我是我想知道它的样子
in the setup of the stateless clients who announced whether there will be like
在无国籍客户的设置中，他们宣布是否会喜欢
a more overhead of the network so that's uh it's interesting to hear um awesome and um maybe uh
网络的另一个开销，所以听到嗯很棒，也许嗯，这很有趣
So, the question about generally what are the current tasks, what are challenges right
因此，关于当前任务的问题，哪些挑战是正确的
now, what is being solved, what is the roadmap, and maybe whether there are some parts that
现在，正在解决的问题，路线图是什么，也许还有一些部分
people could look into, start contributing to.
人们可以研究，开始做出贡献。
I mean, the current roadmap is sync and conversion and pretty much distribution.
我的意思是，当前的路线图是同步和转换，几乎是分发的。
uh contribution well uh there's several there are several areas the the one that uh would be
嗯，捐款好，有几个领域
my favorite and never gets attention is um is implementing vertical trees in uh in other clients
我最喜欢的，从未引起注意的是，um是在其他客户中实施UH的垂直树
so we have a pretty complete implementation in um in uh geth in uh in uh sorry nether mind and
因此，我们在UH Geth的UM中实施了非常完整的实施
Ethereum.js, but there's no implementation to speak of in Rath.
以太坊，但在拉特中没有实施的实施。
In Aragon, it's pretty nascent, so I'm sure they could appreciate some work.
在阿拉贡，这很新生，所以我敢肯定他们可以欣赏一些工作。
And for getting one, Besu.
并得到一个，贝斯。
Besu is on the way, but I'm sure they would appreciate some help as well.
Besu正在路上，但我敢肯定，他们也会感谢您的帮助。
Otherwise, what's an area to contribute to?
否则，有什么贡献的领域？
Well, we want to build stateless clients,
好吧，我们想建立无国籍客户，
So stateless clients are an option.
因此，无状态客户是一个选择。
And otherwise something
否则
that is also not receiving a lot of attention,
这也没有得到很多关注，
it's not directly core protocol related,
它与核心协议无直接相关，
but it's how L2s, DApps are going,
但这就是L2，Dapps的发展，
like compilers are going to handle
像编译器一样
a vertical tree specificities, especially compilers.
垂直树特异性，尤其是编译器。
There's no work done on compilers at the moment.
目前没有对编译器进行的工作。
So that would be an extremely useful contribution.
因此，这将是一个非常有用的贡献。
And then otherwise, I mean, there's plenty of tooling required.
然后，我的意思是，需要大量工具。
We don't really have a lot of support in Block Explorers.
我们在Block Explorers中确实没有很多支持。
There's also some work that can be done,
还有一些可以完成的工作，
although that was already the topic of EPF efforts last year.
尽管这已经是去年EPF努力的主题。
but there's always the zk stuff.
但是总有ZK的东西。
This one, I think, is a bit too early
我认为这还为时过早
to be realistically helpful, but that's an option.
实际上有帮助，但这是一种选择。
There's state expiry,
有州到期，
very good work done by Han last year.
去年Han完成的非常好的工作。
So yeah, maybe see how it interacts
是的，也许看看它的互动方式
with account abstraction.
带有帐户抽象。
If you can build relayers,
如果您可以建立接力者，
there's a ton of things to do.
有很多事情要做。
Honestly, I wouldn't name one that's,
老实说，我不会说一个
you know, the most important, everything is important. Maybe Nessio has
您知道，最重要的是，一切都很重要。也许Nessio有
more ideas?
更多想法？
No, I think I agree with all that list. I mean, we have other, like the previous
不，我认为我同意所有清单。我的意思是，我们还有其他
distribution and all that. I think we have more like decisions
分发等等。我认为我们有更多的决定
to make than really executable tasks that we
要比我们真正可执行的任务
want to get more feedback from client teams and
想从客户团队那里获得更多反馈，
what kind of solutions might make them more comfortable. But I think it
什么样的解决方案可能会使它们更舒适。但我认为
it was a really nice list of things that people can contribute.
这是人们可以贡献的事情的非常好的清单。
So yeah, thanks so much, guys. Um, we are, we are running through almost all the questions
是的，非常感谢，伙计们。嗯，我们是，我们几乎正在解决所有问题
I believe. There's some being answered in the in the discord as well. Thank you so much
我相信。在不和谐中也有一些回答。太感谢了
for joining the discord, by the way, and answering their really appreciated it's a study group.
顺便说一句，加入不和谐，并回答他们真正的赞赏是一个学习小组。
You mentioned the state expiry, it's something I wanted to ask about, because it used to be a bigger thing, it's not mentioned much.
您提到了状态到期，这是我想问的事情，因为这曾经是更大的事情，这并不是太多了。
Do you think that the vertical trees also opened the gates to the state expiry? Is it more feasible with the vertical trees? What is the benefit there?
您是否认为垂直树也打开了州到期的大门？垂直树木更可行吗？那里有什么好处？
Yeah. So yes, it totally makes it feasible or at least more practical.
是的。因此，是的，这完全使其可行或至少更实用。
It's, you know,
你知道，
the problem with vertical trees is that it's both a boon and a bane for,
垂直树的问题在于，它既是福音，又是祸根
for a state expiry.
国家到期。
It's a boon because the proof,
这是一个福音，因为证据，
the proving system makes it so much more practical,
证明系统使其变得更加实用，
but it makes it less relevant at the same time because state growth becomes
但这使其同时较少相关，因为国家的增长变得
less of a problem. So if state growth becomes less of a problem,
少问题。因此，如果国家的增长变得不那么问题，
it's less of a, of a,
它不属于a，
requirement or at least an emergency.
要求或至少紧急。
But there's been some very good work done by
但是有一些很好的工作
Han last year. And I think
去年。我想
in fact, I need to get back to him about the topic.
实际上，我需要回到他的话题上。
I think we have
我想我们有
a good
好
streamlined solution. So there's no
流线型解决方案。所以没有
implementation to speak of currently, but at least there's been
实施目前，但至少有
good work done at the theoretical level such
在理论层面上完成的好工作
that I think it would be interesting to keep digging in this topic,
我认为继续挖掘这个话题会很有趣，
knowing that, once again, unfortunately,
不幸的是，再次知道这一点
vertical trees make it less likely that this will be adopted in the near future
垂直树的可能在不久的将来采用的可能性较小
because it's not as urgent,
因为这不太紧急，
but it's definitely a topic that we'll need to face sooner or later.
但这绝对是我们迟早需要面对的话题。
So I don't think it spells the doom of state expiry.
因此，我认为这不会拼写为国家到期的厄运。
it's just that it's still
只是它仍然
no one really cares about it at the moment
目前没有人真正在乎
that would be it's biggest problem
那将是最大的问题
I care about it
我在乎
I asked you about it because
我问你，因为
I was excited
我很兴奋
I like the proposals when I first ran into it
我第一次遇到的建议
because there is just so much useless stuff
因为有很多无用的东西
in the state that my node needs to be running
在状态下，我的节点需要运行
I have my precious little machine
我有我珍贵的小机器
and I store so much
我存储了很多
unimportant things there
那里不重要的事情
which could expire, hopefully.
希望能过期。
And even in a stateless error, I'm
甚至在无状态错误中，我
going to run as full node as possible.
将尽可能完整的节点运行。
So it would be nice to have more lead.
因此，拥有更多领先优势会很高兴。
Right, but between history expiry,
是的，但是在历史到期之间，
because most of the stuff that is taking space on your disk
因为大多数在磁盘上占用空间的东西
is actually the blocks, the historical blocks,
实际上是街区，历史街区，
the receipts, all that stuff.
收据，所有这些东西。
So we have history expiry, which is another big topic.
因此，我们有历史到期，这是另一个大话题。
I'm not really helping my case here,
我在这里并没有真正帮助我的案子，
but that's also a very important topic.
但这也是一个非常重要的话题。
And this one, you know, some of it we could even do now.
而且，这是我们现在甚至可以做的。
Like, we store the receipts forever.
就像，我们永远存储收据。
Do we need to?
我们需要吗？
Not really.
并不真地。
We, you know, we could, I mean,
我们知道，我的意思是，我们可以
guest has been working on getting rid of the historical blocks,
客人一直在努力摆脱历史街区，
but, you know, other clients might be interested
但是，您知道，其他客户可能会感兴趣
in implementing a history expiry.
在实施历史到期时。
And that's a very interesting topic, too,
这也是一个非常有趣的话题
because you don't really need a hard fork for that.
因为您真的不需要硬叉。
You just need to implement it.
您只需要实施它。
That's it.
就是这样。
There's a few problems with it.
有一些问题。
And okay, I'm going to stop talking about history expiring,
好的，我将停止谈论历史到期，
but that would have a major impact.
但这将产生重大影响。
And then on top of that,
然后最重要的是
vertical trees would have another major impact
垂直树将产生另一个重大影响
because the tree,
因为树，
we found ways of storing the tree
我们找到了存储树的方法
in such a way that it's also going to take less space,
以这样的方式，它也将占用更少的空间
at least theoretically.
至少理论上。
So once you have those two things, history expiry becomes way less of a problem.
因此，一旦有了这两件事，历史到期就不会成为问题。
It's still, you're right, there's a lot of stuff that is completely pointless.
仍然是，您是对的，有很多完全毫无意义的东西。
When, you know, in 50 years who's going to care about your CryptoKitties, right?
您知道，在50岁时，谁会关心您的隐脚式呢？
Most of the people owning CryptoKitties, okay, maybe not in 50 years, but in 100 years,
大多数拥有Cryptokitties的人，好的，也许不是在50年，而是在100年内，
most likely everybody owning a CryptoKitty will be dead. Do we still need it? No.
最有可能每个拥有隐脚智能的人都会死。我们还需要它吗？不。
and more importantly, we'll be running out of people who care about cryptokines.
更重要的是，我们将用尽关心隐脚动力学的人。
So yes, it's quite important in the long run, but in practical terms, in the next 10 years,
因此，是的，从长远来看，这非常重要，但是实际上，在未来10年中，
you will not need state expiry, basically.
基本上，您将不需要状态到期。
Right. Yeah, thanks so much for giving the intro into the history expiry as well,
正确的。是的，非常感谢您将历史介绍到有效期的介绍，
because it's kind of a teaser for a talk later in the study group.
因为这是在研究小组后来进行对话的预告片。
We will have Piper talking about history
我们将让派珀谈论历史
expiring in the full talk, so we will dive into that as well.
在完整的演讲中到期，因此我们也会深入研究。
Thank you so much, Guillaume.
非常感谢您，纪物。
And yeah, folks, I think there are not many other questions
是的，伙计们，我认为还有很多其他问题
that we can answer now.
我们现在可以回答。
We have maybe a few more minutes to go.
我们可能还有几分钟。
Josh, do you have anything?
乔什，你有什么吗？
Um, I am.
嗯，我是。
Yeah.
是的。
So Virkle is sort of slated for the following hard fork after, um, after the
因此，virkle被打算用于以下硬叉之后，嗯，之后
next one, what was sort of like the timeframe you see for actually having
下一个，有点像您看到的时间范围
all this stuff implemented in different clients and, and benchmarked and tested
所有这些内容均在不同的客户中实施，并进行了基准测试和测试
and all of the things ready for a hard work.
以及所有准备辛勤工作的事情。
I was hoping to give the floor to Josh.
我希望将地板交给乔什。
Okay, I'll just give a quick update.
好吧，我只需快速更新。
So I'm extremely optimistic, right?
所以我非常乐观，对吧？
I still believe we can front-run Denkun.
我仍然相信我们可以在丹昆进行领先。
So this is to tell you how optimistic I am.
所以这是告诉你我有多乐观。
But no, from what I see, most of the problems have been solved.
但是，从我所看到的，大多数问题已经解决。
yes, there's still a few open problems like sync,
是的，仍然有一些公开问题，例如同步，
like pre-image distribution,
像图像前分布一样
but this is really a problem
但这确实是一个问题
because a lot of clients have looked at other things
因为很多客户都看过其他事情
instead of looking at vertical trees,
而不是看垂直树，而是
but there's been a lot of progress with clients.
但是客户取得了很多进展。
We have a good support in NetherMind.
我们在Nethermind方面有很好的支持。
We have a pretty good support in Ethereum.js.
我们在以太坊中得到了很好的支持。
yes, BESU is underway, they're making progress as well.
是的，besu正在进行中，他们也取得了进步。
I think next year, a year is realistic.
我认为明年，一年是现实的。
Maybe someone more pessimistic would say a year and a half, two years,
也许更悲观的人会说一年半，两年
but it's definitely ready for its prime, at least.
但这至少已经准备好了。
Awesome. Well, congratulations on that, and good luck front-running Dan Kuhn.
惊人的。好吧，恭喜这件事，祝您好运前跑丹·库恩（Dan Kuhn）。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Yeah, amazing.
是的，很棒。
Thank you so much, guys.
非常感谢，伙计们。
Thank you so much for the presentation,
非常感谢您的演讲，
but especially all the great work you've done
但尤其是您所做的所有出色工作
on the record tree migration
在记录树上迁移
or the whole concept.
或整个概念。
It's great to learn from you.
很高兴向您学习。
Yeah, we are almost at 90 minutes.
是的，我们快90分钟了。
I think we can wrap up here.
我认为我们可以在这里总结。
But again, we really appreciate having you here.
但是，再次，我们非常感谢您在这里。
We appreciate having you in the Discord
我们感谢您在不和谐中
answering questions.
回答问题。
Maybe if there are some more questions
也许还有一些问题
coming, keep an eye on it. People might ping you with something. I hope you folks listening to this
来，请密切关注它。人们可能会用某种东西来ping你。我希望你们听这个
will learn a lot, and we'll have some more documentation on the wiki for vertical trees
会学到很多东西，我们将在Wiki上提供更多文档
later on. Yeah, awesome. Great. Thank you, everybody. We will see you all next Monday
稍后。是的，很棒。伟大的。谢谢大家。我们将在下周一见到你
for a dive into consensus layer architect client architecture with paul from teku
与Teku的Paul一起研究共识层架构师架构
and thanks again gil ignacio josh for your time today thanks appreciate it see you guys bye-bye
再次感谢吉尔·伊格纳西奥·乔什（Gil Ignacio Josh）今天的时间，感谢你们再见
¶¶
¶¶
Thank you.
谢谢。